(soft scratching)
(ascending bells ringing)
(energetic music)
Voiceover: Did you know the idea that people with
autism don't like affection is actually a myth?
Did you know autism doesn't just affect children?
(kissing)
Children with autism grow up to be adults with autism
Man: Oh no!
Voiceover: but compared to children
we know relatively little about the numbers of
adults and their needs in adulthood.
Did you know boys are four times more likely
to develop autism than girls?
Estimates vary between
four to one and fifteen to one.
Did you know 40% of all children with
autism have to wait more than three years
for a clear diagnosis from their doctor?
Did you know people with autism often want to
Short Boy: Hey kid, what's your name?
Voiceover: make friends but due to their disability
find it very difficult?
Boy: He's weird
Sitting Boy: Yeah, totally. Let's go.
Voiceover: Did you know less than 15 percent of
adults with autism are in full-time paid employment,
even though they may have the adequate
cognitive and communicative ability to perform
functional and meaningful tasks and jobs?
The buzz about autism is everywhere these days.
The numbers released by the CDC are
increasing at alarming rates.
It is now more common than diabetes,
cancer, or down syndrome.
With numbers this high it is apparent
that autism touches everyone in some way.
Based on statistics from the
US Department of Education
and other government agencies,
autism is growing at a startling rate
of 10 to 17 percent per year.
At this rate the autism society estimates
that the prevalence of autism could reach
four million Americans in the next decade.
Autism knows no racial, ethnic,
or social boundaries, family income levels,
lifestyle choices, or educational levels,
and can affect any family and any child.
(child crying)
Some families experience autism first hand.
Others experience it second hand,
such as within their communities or social circles.
After we examine all impacts of ASD
including social, economical and educational
it is obvious that we are all affected directly
or indirectly by this disorder.
^Although there are similarities in people
^with ASD, the spectrum is diverse.
^The individuals are so unique
no two are exactly alike.
^What exactly is autism?
We're going to take a look at this question
but go further and consider the lives
of those affected by autism,
learn about the diversity existing within the
diagnosis and explore the different faces of autism.